Guide to the Jewish Orthodox Publication collection, 1914-2004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Jewish Orthodox Publication collection 1914-2004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
29.0 Linear Feet 3,000 Items
Jewish Orthodoxy, the traditional section of Jewry that maintains a religiously observant way of life based on a divinely ordained Torah and its laws, is composed of many groups that differ by certain customs and ideological trends.
This collection documents Jewish Orthodoxy in its various manifestations through ephemeral publications created and distributed by Orthodox Jewish groups in Israel, the United States, and around the world. The materials range in date from 1914-2004, with the bulk of the material published between 1950-1995.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Jewish Orthodox Publication collection was compiled from a gift from the University of Maryland in 2009.
Historical Note
The Jewish Orthodoxy Publication Collection was compiled by Duke University Libraries staff during the processing of a large gift of books and serials from the University of Maryland. These materials, all of which relate directly to Orthodox Judaism, were separated from other print materials because of their ephemeral nature; most are small pamphlets, single issues, or small runs of a periodical or newsletter.
Collection Overview
The collection contains single-issue and short-run serials and ephemeral publications from various Orthodox Jewish groups around the world, including Israel and the United States. The materials range in date from 1914 to 2004, and document a variety of subjects, including social customs, variants of Jewish Orthodoxy, neighborhoods within Israel, and Orthodox education. Jewish Orthodoxy is defined here as the traditional section of Jewry that maintains a religiously observant way of life based on a divinely ordained Torah.
Collection Arrangement
Organized into the folowing series: Agudat Yisra'el; Rabbinical Council- United States; Beit Ya'akov; Children's; Kashrut, Shemitah; Ha-Mizrachi; Haredim; Hasidism; Conference of European Rabbis; Mitnagdim; Ne'emane Ha-torah; Orthodox General; Ramat Elhanan-Bnei Brak; Hozrim Bi'teshuvah; Religious Zionism; Technology and Halakhah; Yad L'Achim; and Yeshivot. Titles arranged alphabetically by Hebrew character within each series.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Hasidim
Jews -- Dietary Laws
Jewish Law
Jews, Oriental
Judaism
Mitnaggedim
Orthodox Judaism
Rabbinical seminaries
Religious Zionism
Sabbatical year (Judaism)
Ultra-Orthodox Jews
Yeshivas
Contents of Collection
- Agudat Yis'rael, 1955-2004, (1.5 linear feet)
  Publications of Agudat Yisra'el, an ultra-orthodox, non-Zionist organization, which was founded in Eastern Europe at the beginning of the twentieth century in order to defend the Jewish traditional way of life, and has eventually become part of the political system in the State of Israel.
  Titles arranged alphabetically by Hebrew character within each subseries.
  - General
    General publications of Agudat Yisra'el.
    - אחדות (Aḥdut) 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Author/Editor: ישראל הורביץ. יצחק אהרן ווייזר
      Bnei Brak
      no. 1
    - בעיות הזמן קובץ מאמרים (beʻayot ha-zeman ḳovets maʼamarim) 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Author/Editor: רפאל ראובן גרוזבסקי
      Bnei Brak: נצח
    - דין וחשבון (Din ṿe-ḥeshbon mugash le-tsire ha-Kenesiyah ha-gedolah ha-ʻolamit) 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Jerusalem: Information Department of Agudath Israel World Organization
      no. 13-21
    - דרכנו (Darkenu) 1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Tel Aviv: אגודת ישראל
      no. 2
    - דרכנו (Darkenu) 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Author/Editor: דוד יונגר
      Bnei Brak: נדפס בדפוס אופסט "ראם"
      no. 3-4; 6
    - דרכנו (Darkenu) 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      no. 11; 14
    - דרכנו (Darkenu) 1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      no. 18 - 19
    - הוסרה חרפת ניוול המת בישראל (Husrah ḥerpat niṿul ha-met be-Yiśraʾel) 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Tel Aviv: הסתדרות אגודת ישראל בא"י
    - הכנסיה הגדולה השניה (ha-Kenesiyah ha-Gedolah ha-Sheniyah) (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Leopoldsgasse: Weltkongress D.Agudas Jisroel
    - המאור (ha-maʹor) (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Author/Editor: אסתר וינברג-אקשטיין
      Tel Aviv: מרכז נשי אגודת ישראל
    - ידיעון (Jedion) 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Antwerpen: Orgaan van de Agoedat Israel in Belgie
      no. Juni
    - ידיעון (Jedion) 1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      no. April
    - ידיעון (Jedion) 1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      no. 4
    - ידיעון (Jedion) 1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      no. 8
    - ידיעון (Jedion) 1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      no. 1; 3-4
    - חומר לשאלת התכוננות וסידור חמדינה היהודית על-פי התורה (Ḥomer li-sheʼelat hitkonenut ṿe-sidur ha-medinah ha-Yehudit ʻal-pi ha-Torah) 1948 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Author/Editor: יצחק לווין
      New York: Research Institute for Post-War Problems of Religious Jewry
    - חנוך לנער בטאון תנועת הנוער הארצית (Ḥanokh La-na'ar) (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Bnei Brak: נר ישראל
    - טל אורות (Ṭal ʼorot) (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Author/Editor: דוד שניאור
      Bnei Brak: אורות
    - מאסף תורני מסורת (Meʼasef Torani Masoret) 1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Bnei Brak: "אשל"
      no. 9
    - מכנסיה לכנסיה (mi-Kenesiyah li-Khenesiyah) 1954 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Jerusalem: הסתדרות אגודת ישראל העולמית
    - ניב המורה (Niv ha-Moreh) 1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Tel Aviv: הסתדרות מורי אגו"י
      no. 37
    - ניב המורה (Niv ha-Moreh) 1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      no. 43, 45
    - ניב המורה (Niv ha-Moreh) 1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      no. 61
    - ניב המורה (Niv ha-Moreh) 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      no. 63
    - ניב המורה (Niv ha-Moreh) 1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      no. 65-66, 69
    - ניב המורה (Niv ha-Moreh) 1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      no. 73, 76
    - ניב המורה (Niv ha-Moreh) 1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      no. 88, 90
    - ניב המורה (Niv ha-Moreh) 1998 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      no. 93-94, 96, 100-101
    - ניב המורה (Niv ha-Moreh) 1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      no. 103, 105, 108-111
    - נר ישראל (Ner Yiśraʾel) 1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Tel Aviv: רשת ישיבות המתמידים "נר ישראל"
    - עם התורה קובץ תורני (Meʼasef 'am ha-torah Ḳovets torani) 1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Brooklyn: Am Hatorah
    - קובץ תורני עם התורה (Ḳovets torani ʻAm ha-Torah) 1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Author/Editor: הרב יחזקאל פלדברגר
      New York: עמפייער פרעסס
      no. 6
    - קובץ תורני עם התורה (Ḳovets torani ʻAm ha-Torah) 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - קובץ תורני עם התורה (Ḳovets torani ʻAm ha-Torah) 1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      no. 5
    - קול התורה (Ḳol ha-Torah) 1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Brooklyn: Keren Hatorah
      no. 42
    - קול התורה (Ḳol ha-Torah)2003 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      no. 53-54
    - קול התורה (Ḳol ha-Torah)2004 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      no. 55
    - קול התורה מאסף תורני (Ḳol ha-Torah meʼasef Torani) 1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      London: אגודת ישראל באירופה
      no. 13
    - קץ המערכה (Ḳets ha-maʻarakhah) 1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Jerusalem: ההסברה של העדה החרדית
    - קריאה נאמנה (Ḳeriʼah neʼemanah) 1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Author/Editor: אליעזר מנחם
      Bene Brak: קבוצת בני ישיבת
    - קרן ארץ ישראל התורתית (Ḳeren Erets Yiśraʼel Ha-toratit) 1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      no. תשרי, חשון
    - שבתי-ה (Shivtiya-h) 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Tel Aviv: הסתדרות בנות אגו"י מחלקת ההדרכה
      no. 28, 30-31
    - תורה עבודה גמילות חסדים (Torah ʻAvodah Gemilut Ḥasadim) 1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Tel Aviv: אמרתנו
      no. 250
    - Report to the Fourth Knessia Gedola () 1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      London: Agudas Israel World Organisation
    - הרס וחילול קברי הקדמונים בארץ ישראל (heres ṿe-ḥilul Ḳivre ha-ḳadmonim be-ʼErets Yiśraʼel) 1976 (Oversize-box 56, Folder 1)
      Jerusalem: מרכז אגודת ישראל
    - קול ישראל (Ḳol Yiśraʼel) 1975 (Oversize-box 56, Folder 2)
      Jerusalem: הסיום השביעי של הדף היומי
    - קול ישראל (Ḳol Yiśraʼel) 1976 (Oversize-box 56, Folder 3)
      no. 4-6; 11; 13-14
    - קול ישראל (Ḳol Yiśraʼel) 1977 (Oversize-box 56, Folder 4)
      no. 16
    - קול ישראל (Ḳol Yiśraʼel) 1978 (Oversize-box 56, Folder 5)
      no. 18-21
    - קול ישראל (Ḳol Yiśraʼel) 1979 (Oversize-box 56, Folder 6)
      no. 23, 26
    - קול ישראל (Ḳol Yiśraʼel) 1980 (Oversize-box 56, Folder 7)
      no. 27-28, 30, 33
    - קול ישראל (Ḳol Yiśraʼel) 1981 (Oversize-box 56, Folder 8)
      no. 34-35
    - קול ישראל (Ḳol Yiśraʼel) 1982 (Oversize-box 56, Folder 9)
      no. 40
    - קול ישראל (Ḳol Yiśraʼel) 1983 (Oversize-box 56, Folder 10)
    - שערים בטאון פועלי אגודת ישראל בארץ ישראל (Sheʻarim biṭʼon poʻale ʼAgudat Yiśraʼel be-ʼErets Yiśraʼel) 1955 (Oversize-box 56, Folder 11)
      Tel Aviv: פועלי אגודת ישראל
    - ששים שנה לאגודת ישראל קובץ יובל (Shishim Shanah la-ʼAgudat Yiśraʼel Ḳovets Yovel) 1972 (Oversize-box 56, Folder 12)
      Jerusalem: Agudath Israel World Organization
  - Children
    Publications of Agudat Yisra'el specifically for children.
    - גליון לנוער (Gilayon la-Noʻar) 1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Bnei Brak: דו שבועון לכלל הנוער החרדי
      no. 678
    - גליון לנוער (Gilayon la-Noʻar) 1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      no. 696
    - גליון לנוער (Gilayon la-Noʻar) 1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      no. 717
    - גליון לנוער (Gilayon la-Noʻar) 1980 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      no. 736
- Rabbinical Council - United States, 1969-1988, (0.25 linear feet)
  Publications of the Orthodox Rabbinical Council of America.
  Titles arranged alphabetically by Hebrew character within the series.
  - הדרום (ha-Darom) 1969 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    New York: הסתדרות הרבנים דאמריקה
    no. 29
  - הדרום (ha-Darom) 1976 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    no. 43
  - הדרום (ha-Darom) 1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    no. 46
  - הדרום (ha-Darom) 1988 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    no. 57
- Bet Ya'akov, 1945-1997, (1.5 linear feet)
  Publications of the Beit Ya'akov network of Orthodox schools for Jewish girls.
  - הארות והגיונות על שירי התבוננות ומחשבה מוסרית (Heʼarot ṿe-hegyonot ʻal shire hitbonenut u-maḥashavah musarit) 1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Bnei Brak: בית יעקב
  - העמוד השלישי (Heʻamud ha-shlishi) 1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Author/Editor: גמילות חסדים
    Tel Aviv: בית יעקב
  - העתיד קובץ מאמרים (he-ʻatid ḳovets maʼamarim) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Author/Editor: מאיר שצרנסקי
  - מכון בית יעקב למורות (Mekhon Bet Yaʻaḳov le-Morot) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Jerusalem: The Beth Jacob Seminary for Teachers in Jerusalem
  - יפה תלמוד תורה (Yafeh Talmud Torah) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Haifa: בית יעקב
  - קובץ זכרון לעטרת ראשנו מורינו ורבינו (Ḳovets Zikaron la-ʻAṭeret Roshenu Morenu ṿe-Rabenu) 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Author/Editor: י. א. וולף
  - קולמוס קובץ ספרותי (Ḳulmos Ḳovets Sifruti) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Beth Jacob Teachers Institute (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Jerusalem: Beth Jacob Teacher's Institute
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1945 (Oversize-box 56, Folder 13)
    Jerusalem: מרכז בית יעקב באר״י
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1959-1960 (Oversize-box 56, Folder 14)
    no. 1 - 16
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1961 (Oversize-box 56, Folder 15)
    vol. 2, no. 18, 20-22
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1961-1962 (Oversize-box 57, Folder 1)
    vol. 3 - 4, no. 25, 29-40
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1963 (Oversize-box 57, Folder 2)
    vol. 4, no. 41, 44-46
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1964 (Oversize-box 57, Folder 3)
    vol. 5, no. 59
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1965 (Oversize-box 57, Folder 4)
    vol. 6, no. 65-76
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1966 (Oversize-box 57, Folder 5)
    vol. 7, no. 77-88
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1967 (Oversize-box 57, Folder 6)
    vol. 8, no. 90, 93, 100
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1968 (Oversize-box 57, Folder 7)
    vol. 9, no. 103, 110-111
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1970 (Oversize-box 57, Folder 8)
    vol. 11, no. 123-124, 126, 131
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1971 (Oversize-box 58, Folder 1)
    vol. 12, no. 132
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1973 (Oversize-box 58, Folder 2)
    vol. 14, no. 163-164
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1976 (Oversize-box 58, Folder 3)
    vol. 17, no. 193
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1978 (Oversize-box 58, Folder 4)
    vol. 19, no. 217-218, 221
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1979 (Oversize-box 58, Folder 5)
    vol. 20, no. 232-233
  - בית יעקב (Bet Yaʻaḳov) 1980 (Oversize-box 58, Folder 6)
    vol. 21, no. 238-239
  - מכון בית יעקב למורות ירושלים אדר תשלא (Mekhon Bet Yaʻaḳov le-Morot Yerushalayim Adar 1971) 1980 (Oversize-box 58, Folder 7)
    Author/Editor: פנחס יעקב הכהן לוין
    no. 22
  - מכון בית יעקב למורות (Mekhon Bet Yaʻaḳov le-Morot) 1971 (Oversize-box 58, Folder 8)
    Jerusalem: פרסום קולע
  - מעלות (Maʻalot) 1986 (Oversize-box 58, Folder 9)
    Jerusalem: מכון בית יעקב למורות
    vol. 18, no. 1 - 3
  - מעלות (Maʻalot) 1987 (Oversize-box 58, Folder 10)
    vol. 19, no. 5; 8
  - מעלות (Maʻalot) 1988 (Oversize-box 58, Folder 11)
    vol. 20, no. 9
  - מעלות (Maʻalot) 1989 (Oversize-box 58, Folder 12)
    no. 12
  - מעלות (Maʻalot) 1990 (Oversize-box 58, Folder 13)
    no. 17
  - מעלות (Maʻalot) 1992 (Oversize-box 58, Folder 14)
    no. 25
  - מעלות (Maʻalot) 1997 (Oversize-box 58, Folder 15)
    no. 34
- Children, 1947-2000, (1.0 linear feet)
  Publications for children of various Orthodox communities.
  - אלבום מורי האומה (Album more ha-ʼumah) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    עלית
  - הלכות ומנהגי פורים המשולש וערב פסח שחל בשבת (Halakhot u-minhage Purim ha-meshulash ṿe-ʻErev Pesaḥ she-ḥal be-Shabat) (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Author/Editor: ראובן ברים
    Jerusalem
  - יפה בעתו (Yafeh be-ʻito) 1990 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Author/Editor: י. פ. ה. ביללער
    New York: self published
    no. February-May; June-July
  - יפה בעתו (Yafeh be-ʻito) 1991 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    vol. 2, no. 6 - 10
  - יפה בעתו (Yafeh be-ʻito) 1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    vol. 2, no. 11 - 14
  - יפה בעתו (Yafeh be-ʻito) 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    vol. 3, no. 15-16; 18-19
  - יפה בעתו (Yafeh be-ʻito) 1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    vol. 3, no. 20-21; 23
  - יפה בעתו (Yafeh be-ʻito) 1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    vol. 4, no. 25, 28-31
  - יפה בעתו (Yafeh be-ʻito) 1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    vol. 7, no. 57, 59, 62-63
  - יפה בעתו (Yafeh be-ʻito) 1998 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    vol. 9, no. 89
  - יפה בעתו (Yafeh be-ʻito) 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    vol. 10, no. 95-96, 99
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1947 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    New York: Torah Umesorah, Inc.
    vol. 2, no. 8 - 9
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    vol. 3, no. 1 - 5
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1948-1949 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    vol. 4, no. 1; 3-4
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1950 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    no. June
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    vol. 7, no. 4 - 5
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    vol. 8, no. 1 - 3
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1953 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    vol. 9, no. 3
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1962 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    vol. 16, no. 6 - 7
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1962 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    vol. 17, no. 3
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1967 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    vol. 21, no. 7
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    vol. 23, no. 2-4; 7-8
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1972 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    vol. 26, no. 6
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1972 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    vol. 27, no. 3
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    vol. 28, no. 8
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    vol. 30, no. 7
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    vol. 40, no. 4 - 6
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    vol. 41, no. 3; 8
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    vol. 42, no. 1; 7
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    vol. 44, no. 4
  - עולמנו: Our World (ʻOlamenu) 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    vol. 45, no. 3
  - עולמנו: Nuestro Mundo (ʻOlamenu) 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Mexico: Torah Umesorah, Inc.
    vol. 1, no. Kislev, Tevet, Adar, Tamuz
  - עולמנו: Nuestro Mundo (ʻOlamenu) 1981 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    no. Tishrei
- Kashrut, Shemitah, 1955-1994, (0.25 linear feet)
  Orthodox publications related to dietary and shemitah laws and agricultural matters.
  - בנתיבות ההלכה (Bi-netivot ha-halakhah) 1993 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Jerusalem: באהלי תורה
    vol. 1
  - דבר השמיטה (Devar ha-shemiṭah) 1980 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Jerusalem: בהשגחת הבד"ץ
  - דבר השמיטה (Devar ha-shemiṭah) 1994 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    no. 41
  - הוראות לשנת השמיטה (horaʼot li-shenat ha-shemiṭah) 1980 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Jerusalem: המועצה הדתית ירושלים
  - הלכות והליכות לקט לפסח (Halakhot ṿa-halikhot leḳeṭ le-Fesaḥ) 1968 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Author/Editor: ירמיהו רלב"ג
    Jerusalem: מחלקת הכשרות
  - המכון לחקר החקלאות ע"פ התורה (Ha-makhon le-ḥeḳer ha-Ḥaḳlaʼut ʻa. p. ha-torah) 1973 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Tel Aviv: המדע בשרות התורה
    vol. 5
  - מהדרין (Mehadrin) 1991 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Jerusalem: "משכיל לדוד- מפעלי תורה והוראה"
  - מהדרין (Mehadrin) 1994 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - מנחת ירושלים (Minḥat Yerushalayim) 1994 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Jerusalem: מדרש "מנחת ירושלים"
  - ערך שביעית (ʻErekh Sheviʻit) 1938 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Author/Editor: רבני ארץ-ישראל
    Jerusalem: קרן השמיטה
  - קובץ הכשרות במטבח המודרני (Ḳovets ha-kashrut ba-miṭbaḥ ha-moderni) 1988 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - קובץ הלכתי מפרי הארץ (Ḳovets hilkhati Mi-peri ha-arets) (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Jerusalem: בית המועצה האזורית נחל שורק יד-בנימין
  - קונטרס חקר הלכה (Ḳunṭres Ḥeḳer halakhah) 1955 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    Author/Editor: ירוחם פישל גרוסברג
    Jerusalem: המסורה
  - קונטרס קדושת שביעית שנת השמיטה תש"מ (Ḳunṭres Ḳedushat Sheviʻit Shenat ha-Shemiṭah 740) 1980 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Tel Aviv: מערכת "קדושת שביעית"
  - Kosher Butchers Voice 1955 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    New York: Brooklyn Kosher Butchers Association
    vol. 22, no. 36-39
  - Kosher Butchers Voice 1957 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    vol. 24, no. 34
- Ha-Mizrachi, 1957-2001, (1.5 linear feet)
  Publications of the Ha-Mizrachi movement, an orthodox Zionist movement established in Eastern Europe in the early twentieth century which aspired to combine the observance of the commandments with the return to Zion. Included are also publications of Ha-Po'el Ha-Mizrachi, a branch of the Ha-Mizrachi movement with labor and pioneering orientation.
  - General
    General publications of the Ha-Mizrachi movement.
    - ברקאי (Barḳai) 1983 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Author/Editor: הרב שאול ישראלי
      Jerusalem: התועה העולמית של המזרחי
    - ברקאי (Barḳai) 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      התועה העולמית של המזרחי
    - ברקאי (Barḳai) 1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      no. 3
    - ברקאי (Barḳai) 1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - גוילין (Geṿilin) 1957 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Tel Aviv: המפלגה הדתית לאומית בישראל (המזרחי הפועל המזרחי)
    - גוילין (Geṿilin) 1958 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      no. 3; 6-7
    - גוילין (Geṿilin) 1964 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      no. 19-20
    - גוילין (Geṿilin) 1965 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      no. 21-22
    - גוילין (Geṿilin) 1967 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      no. 27-28
    - גוילין (Geṿilin) 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      no. 1 - 2
    - גוילין (Geṿilin) 1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      no. גליון מיוחד לזכר
    - גוילין (Geṿilin) 1994 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - מאמרי הצבי (Maʼamre ha-Tsevi) 1980 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Author/Editor: צבי הרכבי ז"ל
      יוצא לאור ע"י בני המשפחה
    - מדע ואמונה (madaʻ ṿe-ʼemunah) 1947 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Jerusalem: איתאח
    - שבילין (Shevilin) 1963 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Author/Editor: כ. פ. טכורש
      Tel Aviv: בטאון חבר הרבנים ליד המזרחי והפועל המזרחי
    - שבילין (Shevilin) 1964 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      no. 6 - 7
    - שבילין (Shevilin) 1965 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      no. 8 - 9
    - שבילין (Shevilin) 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      no. 12 - 13
    - שבילין (Shevilin) 1970 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      no. 25-26
  - Ha-po'el Ha-Mizrachi
    Publications of Ha-Po'el Ha-Mizrachi, a branch of the Ha-Mizrachi movement with labor and pioneering orientation.
    - מצפה (Mitspeh) 1963 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      Jerusalem: המפלגה הדתית לאומית והסתדרות הפועל המזרחי
      no. 7
    - מצפה (Mitspeh) 1965 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - מצפה (Mitspeh) 1967 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      no. 18-19
    - שבת בשבתו (Shabat Be-shabato) 1985 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      Tel Aviv: העמותה לתודעה יהודית בשיתוף עם הסתדרות הפועל המזרחי בארץ-ישראל
      no. 47-55
    - שבת בשבתו (Shabat Be-shabato) 1986 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      no. 64-72, 74-107
    - שבת בשבתו (Shabat Be-shabato) 1987 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      no. 108-109, 111-126, 128-138, 140, 142-159
    - שבת בשבתו (Shabat Be-shabato) 1988 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      no. 160-213
    - שבת בשבתו (Shabat Be-shabato) 1989 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      no. 214-243, 245-246, 251-264
    - שבת בשבתו (Shabat Be-shabato) 1990 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      no. 270-317
    - שבת בשבתו (Shabat Be-shabato) 1991 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      no. 318-343
    - שבת בשבתו (Shabat Be-shabato)2001 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      no. 870
    - שנתון (Shenaton) 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Author/Editor: משה קרונה
      Jerusalem: התנועה העולמית המזרחי-הפועל המזרחי
    - שנתון (Shenaton) 1988 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Haredim, 1952-1995, (2.5 linear feet)
  Publications of ultra-orthodox Jewish communities. Haredim communities are characterized by strict understanding of and adherence to the halakhah (Jewish law) and by various levels of opposition to Zionism and to the open society.
  - Education
    Publications about Haredim education.
    - ארצות הברית פרקי הסטוריה (ʼArtsot ha-berit pirḳe hisṭoryah) 1960 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Jerusalem: מרכז החנוך העצמאי
    - החינוך העצמאי במערכות (Ha-ḥinukh ha-ʻatsmaʼi Be-maʻarkhot) 1991 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      החינוך העצמאי
    - מרוה לצמא (Marṿeh la-Tsame) 1979 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Author/Editor: ישראל פולק
      Bnei Brak: ארגון בנות ישראל
      no. 127
    - מרוה לצמא (Marṿeh la-Tsame) 1980 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      no. 137, 141
    - מרוה לצמא (Marṿeh la-Tsame) 1984 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      vol. 8, no. 395
    - מרוה לצמא (Marṿeh la-Tsame) 1993 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      vol. 17, no. 911
    - מרוה לצמא (Marṿeh la-Tsame) 1996 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      vol. 20, no. 1056
    - 5 דקות הלכה יומית (5 Daḳot halakhah yomit) 1980 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      ושננתם לבניך החנוך העצמאי
      no. 1 - 4
    - 5 דקות הלכה יומית (5 Daḳot halakhah yomit) undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
      no. 1; 3
    - ניצוצי אור (Nitsotse Or) 1980 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Jerusalem: מכון "אור הצפון" להוצאת ספרי חינוך
    - ניצוצי אור (Nitsotse Or) 1981 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      vol. 2, no. 11-12, 15, 19
    - ניצוצי אור (Nitsotse Or) 1982 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      vol. 3, no. 23, 25-27, 32
    - ניצוצי אור (Nitsotse Or) 1983 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      vol. 4, no. 35, 37, 40, 43-50, 54-55
    - ניצוצי אור (Nitsotse Or) 1984 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      vol. 5, no. 63-68, 70-74, 76, 79-82, 84
    - סדר ברכת המזון וקריאת שמע לילדי ישראל ותשב"ר בחדרים הכשרים (Seder Birkat ha-Mazon u-Ḳeriʼat Shemaʻ Le-yalde Yiśraʼel) 1976 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Jerusalem: חורבת רבי יהודה החסיד
    - קונטרס נתיבי החנוך (Ḳunṭres netive ha-ḥinukh) 1961 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Author/Editor: שלום נח ברזבסקי
      Jerusalem: ראש ישיבת בית אברהם ירושלים